Hey everybody, Packers president and CEO
Ed Policy joined us from the league
meetings and Ed, as I understand it,
growing up, you came to these things.
What's it like to return as the Packers
president and CEO? Uh thanks, Larry.
Well, first off, uh it's great to be
with you down here in Arizona. And yeah,
I've been coming to these for quite some
time. I think my first one was actually
at this very resort. I remember when I
was about 11 years old, my father was
working for the 49ers back then. I was
kind of shushed away from the pool
because my father and Bill Walsh were in
a heated discussion using some language
that I think my mother didn't want me to
hear.
You have your football leadership,
Brian, Matt, and Russ in place for the
foreseeable future. Is that a comforting
thought as you move forward? Yeah, it
sure is. I I couldn't be happier and I
couldn't be more confident about the
three people that we have in place. You
know, I I've known Russ Ball for over 25
years. I think he and I worked together
with the Arena Football League. I've
worked with Brian now for 14 years and
and was part of bringing Matt in 7 years
ago. So, I couldn't be more confident in
them.
Uh really excited about the future with
all three of those guys. I've seen where
building on and maintaining your
presence in the league is one of your
priorities. Is that already happening?
It it is and you know, things like these
annual meetings are critical to really
build that. I would say uh you know, by
way of example, I now sit on many of the
business and policy setting committees
that the league has and uh I'm really
excited because for the first time our
head coach sits on the head coaches sub
advisory committee and our GM sits on
the uh GMAC, which is the GM advisory
committee. So, I think the Packers have
more of a voice than ever at these
meetings. Now, you were part of a number
of votes this morning. Anything out of
that that you would consider the
headline act? You know, maybe the
headline is that it's nowhere near as
dramatic as it was last year, if you
remember. We had a lot of discussion
about the tush push and I'm glad that
we're not talking about that this year.
I think there's an interesting tweak to
the new kickoff rule. Now, any team can
declare an onside kick at any point in
the game. Last year, [music] it was just
uh you had to be the losing team and it
had to be in the fourth quarter.
During your informal session with the
local media guys yesterday, you made a
point of saying and emphasizing the fact
that Packers are in great shape right
now, but you have to approach things,
and I love the phrase, with a healthy
paranoia. Could you elaborate a little
bit?
>> Sure. Well, yeah, you know, it starts
with recognizing the fact that the
Packers are an extreme anomaly. We're
one of one, there's nothing else like us
given our our unique ownership structure
and we do have to compete with the rest
of the the other 31 teams in the NFL and
they have access to money and capital
that the Packers don't have in a few
forms. Obviously, they're owned by very
wealthy owners and a few, you know, more
recent dynamics, they have access to
private equity money and not just
private equity, but just more limited
partners buying minority interest in
their team. So, any other team now can
raise hundreds of millions of dollars by
simply selling non-controlling limited
partnerships in their team and and
again, giving up equity, but certainly
not giving up any control. You've also
seen an increase in the the amount of
public money being invested in the
stadiums across the country and in and
other markets, we don't have access to
that right now. So, with all of that,
the fact that we've got to have got to
have a really successful business off
the field to be able to compete on the
field with all those other teams, we
[music] just have to be really smart,
really forward-looking, and um on top of
some of these trends.
Ed, moving forward, is there a biggest
challenge on the horizon for the Green
Bay Packers? Yeah, I I would say it's um
competition. The NFL [music] has never
been more competitive both on and off
the field. You saw the games last year
were closer than they've ever been. It
feels like so many of the teams are just
kind of bunched together. The parity's
never been better than it is. I think
the championship belongs to anybody next
year, which means it belongs to us.
We've just got to reach out and take it.
Touchdown, Green Bay Packers!